That brings us to talking about the difference between client-side and server-side code.
接下来谈谈客户端和服务器端代码的区别
I think the easiest way to think about server and client-side code is that
我觉得下面的方式可以容易地区分客户端和服务器端
servers are set up at the beginning to handle anything outside of what browsers can do.
服务器是最先搭建好的 处理一切不在浏览器中执行的任务
One example of that is to save data produced while someone's within the app.
比如存储用户使用应用时所产生的数据
Client code on the other hand,
与之相反
represents all your code that the browser executes,
客户端代表所有在浏览器中运行的代码
and all the code that the users will see the end product of.
和用户访问最终产品的的代码
It's probably helpful to think about browsers itself for a moment.
了解一下浏览器或许会对我们厘清概念有所帮助
Remember that browsers such as Chrome or Safari
以 Chrome 或者 Safari 为例
are actually applications that have the ability to do things,
它们都是功能强大的软件
amazing things in the case of browser applications,
可以完成很多浏览器的任务
which can execute HTML, JavaScript,
比如运行 HTML
and CSS natively and interactively.
JavaScript CSS
So really browsers handle a lot of
浏览器的确
the heavy lifting when it comes to runtime for our code.
做了大量工作
But for everything else,
但是其他事
there's the server side.
都是服务器干的
Now let's get into what it really looks like to make a post request on the client side.
我们来看一下客户端发起一个 POST 请求都做了什么
So far, we've been in our server side code,
到目前为止 我们将目光主要放在服务器端
which as you'll remember is where we set up our port,
比如配置端口
setup express to use our middleware,
使用中间件
and now we're going to move over to the client side.
现在让我们将目光转向客户端
Okay. So here, inside of an async function which we'll cover in the next lesson,
在异步函数中 异步函数将会在下一节课学习
we've set up a post route.
访问一个 POST 路由
We've set our posts route with const response,
将结果赋给 const response
we've asked it to fetch a URL which is where we'll want to make the post to,
我们 fetch 一个 目的 URL
and then here under method is where we set the type of request we want to make.
紧接着指明请求的种类
I've requested a post route because I want to post data somewhere,
这里使用 POST 因为我想发送一些数据
but we also could get data,
当然也可以 GET
or put data, or delete data entries.
PUT 甚至 DELETE 数据
Some of this stuff is boilerplate that you need to include,
这里很多都是模板代码
but it's still is important.
它们是必不可少的
But the really juicy stuff comes down to data types.
但是数据类型是我们真正需要关心的
So here on the header as you'll see,
在 HTTP 头中
we've said that we want our application to run on JSON data.
指定使用 JSON
So the really important thing is to make sure that the body of
那么请求体中也必须使用
any request that we send matches that type of data.
相应的数据类型
So because servers naturally deal with that as strings,
由于服务器端用的是字符串
but we want to deal with it as JSON,
因此需要使用 JSON.stringify 方法
we've used the method JSON.stringify to turn our data into JSON data.
将数据转换为 JSON